Scott Malone

linkedin.com/in/scottmatmalone Scott.Malone@student.uts.edu.au 0432 573 112

Career Objective

Currently studying a diploma in Professional Engineering Practice, Bachelor of Electrical Engineering after spending the last ten years as a licenced carpenter. I'm looking for a challenging and innovative career at the forefront of technology. I began to develop a passion for maths and engineering during my first physics class, when we learned how to calculate how long water would take to boil in a kettle, to the second.

Education

Diploma of Professional Engineering Practice Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical)

Feb 2016 - Dec 2022(expected)

University of Technology Sydney (UTS)

- Finished all Electrical Engineering core subjects
- Also involves subjects such as Project Management, Entrepreneurship, Economics and Finance

Tertiary Preparation Certificate IV(TPC)

Feb 2014 - Dec 2015

TAFE Sydney Institute, Ultimo

Certificate III Carpentry

Feb 2010 - Dec 2012

Randwick TAFE

Technical Skills

Languages C, VHDL, MATLAB.

Software Sublime Text 3, Quartus Prime II (lite), MATLAB R2019a, Microsoft

office

Power tools Accurate and safe use of most to all construction power tools

Plans Can read building schematics and technical drawings Circuit Analysis Can design and analyse basic electronic circuits.

Electrical tools Oscilloscopes, function generators, multimeters, DC/AC power

supply

Certified Carpenter Qualified to perform all carpentry duties on domestic and commercial

construction sites

Experience

Trainer & Assessor (Carpentry Certificate III) AHMI Oct 2019 - Current

- Apply strong communication skills when presenting theory to classes of up to 30+ mature age international students
- Demonstrate technical concepts using free body diagrams on white boards
- Design quizzes, assignments and real-world application exercises with short notice, based on the presentations supplied. Plan and execute tasks for students so that they are completed within a deadline. Assess student's competence and ensure they graduate with fully executable skills

Carpenter 2006 - Current

Sole Trader

 Apply strong workplace communication skills with builders (B2B), clients (B2C) and other tradesman to ensure a correct and smooth job. This is done verbally or by reading schematics or drawing diagrams to illustrate an example of the finished product, etc.

• High attention to detail and quality when working on high end multimillion-dollar projects.

Relevant Projects

Fundamentals of C language University of Technology Sydney Aug 2018 - Nov 2018

Designed a program to collect, store and retrieve data. The theme was Sydnev flights.

Requirements:

- Ask the user to select from multiple options
- The program required the user to input a name and address to store on the system
- Other options were to update details, retrieve stored data either by username or flight number from the database, and close program
- The user had to be notified of invalid inputs
- The use of string functions, pointers, arrays, structures, branches and standard library functions had to be used

Introduction to Data Engineering

Mar 2019 - June 2019

University of Technology Sydney

Programming in MATLAB. Designed a program to optimise a terminal/concentrator layout with requirements. It was required to design a system that can calculate the minimum cost to run a terminal/concentrator layout. This project used machine learning algorithms and a probability equation.

- It was required to build a 12 x 7 matrix as a simulation to the terminal.
- MATLAB controls and probability equations had to be used on each element in the matrix.
- Random number generator function was used as an input to the MATLAB algorithm.
- Controls in conjunction with the probability equation determined the smallest possible combination for upkeep cost of the system.
- A plot was used to display the decrease in cost each time a loop in the algorithm was used.

Core Skills

Workplace Communication – As a carpenter it was required to read and explain construction plans, problem solve as a team and differentiate language/terminology between customer and builder.

Public Speaking – Working as a carpentry teacher I often speak for 4-5hrs at a time presenting theoretical concepts to a class of 30+ students. I need to be able to articulate my speech in a manner that is clear to understand, while connecting with the audience to make sure I keep their attention. From this experience I have developed a confidence in public speaking.

Project leadership, organisation and management skills – As a leading hand carpenter I managed labourers and other carpenters by dedicating jobs to work efficiently in a sequential method required to build or renovate homes. Moreover, I had to plan ahead by measuring and having tools and materials available on the job when required.

Hobbies and Interests

Rugby Union, Surfing, Camping, Reading, and Theories about the Universe

Referees

Available upon request.